Kenta Kudo

London, United Kingdom Email: yd37574@gmail.com

Phone: 07397322375

Professional Sumary

Self-disciplined software engineer with a passion for solving critical issues with high focus on the true nature of the problems and engineering expertise. An engineer with wide range of experience who is addicted to simple solutions which solves difficult problems with high efficiency. Punctual practitioner, logical thinker, and diligent learner who enjoys leading organisations to success coping with team.

Skills

Infrastructure

MySQL, GCP, docker, kubernetes, ansible, terraform

Backend

PHP, Golang, Python, OOP, TDD, DDD, Design Pattern, SQL

Mobile

iOS, Swift, Objective-C, Reactive Programming, MVVM

Frontend

JavaScript, knockout js

Others

machine learning, system programming, Raspberry Pi, design, agile

Work Experience

Junior backend engineer | Mercari UK

December 2016 – Present

Mercari is the most successful e-commerce ex-unicorn in Japan. I, as a backend engineer, have wide range of responsibilities. I write micro-services in Golang and configure deployment using GAE, GCE, Kubernetes and Spinnaker. I also develop large userbase application written in PHP using OOP and TDD practices. If needed, I run DB migrations and batch commands on production as well.

iOS Engineer | Smart Tech Ventures

May 2015 – March 2017

Coping with the team of six, I, as an iOS engineer, developed e-commerce client app using MVC architecture in Swift and Objective-C. In the other project, I wrote health care application from scratch alone introducing MVVM architecture and Reactive Programming.

Education

The University of Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan

2011-2015

Bachelor of Engineering | Aeronautical and Astronautical Engineering

Interests

I embrace minimal life style, and love watching movies (40+/yr), reading books (80+/yr), exercising (6days/w), and traveling (20+ countries so far). Developing my skills is a great fun for me, and worked on personal projects such as building ML models that categorise fashion items from images and implementing original OS which works on Raspberry Pi.

Links

Portfolio: kentakudo.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kenta-kudo-6a4b15a8/

GitHub: https://github.com/KentaKudo